<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Startup_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-Startup_Guide-Starting_Up_Salix_OS">
	<title>Starting Up Salix OS</title>
	 <para>

	</para>
	 <section id="sect-Startup_Guide-Starting_Up_Salix_OS-Introduction">
		<title>Introduction</title>
		 <section id="sect-Startup_Guide-Introduction-Downloading_Salix_OS">
			<title>Downloading Salix OS</title>
			 <para>
				The latest Salix OS or Salix Live releases are freely and easily available as ISO image files from the Salix OS <ulink url="http://www.salixos.org/wiki/index.php?title=Download">download page</ulink>.
			</para>
			 <para>
				An ISO image is an archive file of an optical disc. It can be easily rendered or burned to a DVD or CD by using media authoring or disc burning software. The resulting CD must not contain the .iso file; if it does, you have made a mistake in the process.
			</para>
			 <para>
				It is recommended, if possible, to verify the integrity of your downloaded file by comparing its <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Md5sum">md5sum</ulink> file with the original one uploaded besides the corresponding ISO image file by Salix OS. This ensures that your downloaded image file matches exactly with the one provided on the Salix OS website, and minimises the possibility of installation errors later on.
			</para>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-Startup_Guide-Introduction-What_is_a_Live_CD_USB">
			<title>What is a Live CD / USB?</title>
			 <para>
				A Live CD is a CD-ROM holding a self-contained bootable and fully functional operating system. It loads into memory using only the data provided on the CD. It will not modify any operating system or data present on its host computer and will leave no trace after shutdown.
			</para>
			 <para>
				A Live USB flash drive is similar to a Live CD, but it can have the added functionality of automatically and transparently writing changes back to its bootable medium.
			</para>
			 <para>
				Salix Live is the Live CD version of <ulink url="http://www.salixos.org/">Salix OS</ulink>. You can therefore safely use it to 'test drive' Salix OS without having to install anything on your computer. You will thus be able to determine whether and to what extent Salix OS is compatible with your particular hardware configuration and if it suits your personal taste.
			</para>
			 <para>
				If you are fully satisfied with your Live experience of Salix OS, you can then proceed to install it with the help of the Salix Live Installer.
			</para>
			 <para>
				Salix Live will also come in handy as a mobile solution if you wish to carry Salix OS everywhere you go, or if you need to perform some basic rescue operation such as fixing an ailing LILO bootloader with Lilo Setup, configuring some partitions with Gparted, etc.
			</para>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-Startup_Guide-Introduction-Creating_a_Salix_Live_USB_Key">
			<title>Creating a Salix Live USB Key</title>
			 <orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Open the .iso file using a software archiver (file-roller, xarchiver, 7-zip, iso-master, …).
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Extract all files and folders (boot, packages and Salix Live) to your USB root directory.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Go to the "boot" directory on the USB key.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						If you're running on Unix (Linux, BSD, Mac OS X), just run the file called “install-on-USB.sh”. If you're on Windows, just run the file called “install-on-USB.cmd” instead.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</orderedlist>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-Startup_Guide-Introduction-Booting_from_a_Salix_Installation_CDDVDUSB_Key">
			<title>Booting from a Salix Installation CD/DVD/USB Key</title>
			 <para>
				Your computer must be set to boot on the optical drive / USB port first before defaulting to the internal hard disk drive.
			</para>
			 <para>
				If that is not the case, you need to first modify the <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BIOS">BIOS</ulink> setting, usually by pressing the Del key or the F2 key (or some other key combinations depending on your machine). Once in the BIOS, find the "boot menu" or similar and set the order of the boot devices properly, with your optical drive/USB port in the first position. Save your changes and reboot your computer.
			</para>
			 <para>
				Insert the Salix OS (Live)CD/DVD or USB key, and start up your computer.
			</para>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-Startup_Guide-Introduction-Salix_Live_Boot_Menu">
			<title>Salix Live Boot Menu</title>
			 <mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="./images/m4f770b90.png" width="500" />
				</imageobject>
				 <textobject>
					<phrase>Screenshot of Salix Live Boot Menu</phrase>
				</textobject>

			</mediaobject>
			 <para>
				The first screen to greet you will enable you to select your language. Once you have selected your language, simply press on the Enter key to activate your choice.
			</para>
			 <para>
				On the following menu, you will be given the possibility to change your keyboard map if the default one for your language does not suit you.
			</para>
			 <mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="./images/m2a61f76.png" width="500" />
				</imageobject>
				 <textobject>
					<phrase>Screenshot of Boot Menu edition options</phrase>
				</textobject>

			</mediaobject>
			 <para>
				You also have the possibility to modify most default boot settings (see <xref linkend="sect-Startup_Guide-Advanced_Live_CD_Options-Advanced_Boot_Options" />).
			</para>
			 <para>
				Simply press Enter on the default menu entry: Start Salix Live and a moment later you will see Salix starting up.
			</para>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-Startup_Guide-Introduction-Root_Password">
			<title>Root Password</title>
			 <para>
				For a system wide change, such as installation of an application, you are required to type in the administrator's password (the “root” or “superuser” password).
			</para>
			 <note>
				<title>Root Password</title>
				 <para>
					The password for Salix Live is <emphasis role="bold">live</emphasis> for all the Salix Live editions.
				</para>

			</note>

		</section>
		

	</section>
	
	 <section id="sect-Startup_Guide-Starting_Up_Salix_OS-Preparing_Salix_Installation">
		<title>Preparing Salix Installation</title>
		 <section id="sect-Startup_Guide-Preparing_Salix_Installation-Before_starting">
			<title>Before starting</title>
			 <para>
				Installing Salix OS on your computer is simple. But before starting, it is wise to check the following points:
			</para>
			 <orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Have you backed-up all the important files you have?
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Check if your computer comes with Linux-friendly/supported hardware*
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Recommended running specification (Intel PIII 1 GHz, 512 Mb RAM, 8Gb HD space, or equivalent, though a lower spec machine may run without a problem)
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						At least one separate <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disk_partitioning">partition</ulink> dedicated for Salix on your computer
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</orderedlist>
			 <para>
				* Although it is possible to install Linux on a Mac computer, you have to install a bootcamp software called rEFIt beforehand. Certain file systems, such as xfs, cannot be used with a Mac.
			</para>
			 <para>
				The easiest way to check the compatibility of your computer is to use one of the available Salix OS Live editions.
			</para>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-Startup_Guide-Preparing_Salix_Installation-Partition_Management">
			<title>Partition Management</title>
			 <mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="./images/m4548ab69.png" width="500" />
				</imageobject>
				 <textobject>
					<phrase>Screenshot of Gparted</phrase>
				</textobject>

			</mediaobject>
			 <para>
				Before installing Salix (from the live CD or not), you need to have the necessary partition space available on your system, and if the computer does not have a separate partition for Linux, you must create one before installing Salix OS.
			</para>
			 <para>
				It is advisable to back up any important files before modifying the partition table.
			</para>
			 <para>
				Every Salix Live CD comes with <ulink url="http://gparted.sourceforge.net/docs/help-manual/C/gparted_manual.html">Gparted</ulink>, which will enable you to change the partition organisation on a disk device while preserving the contents of the partitions. You may with to use this application to create/re-organise your partition table.
			</para>
			 <para>
				Alternatively, if you have an unformatted partition, unallocated disk space, or an existing partition you do not use, you can create or rewrite a new partition table using <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cfdisk">Cfdisk</ulink> (which comes with the Salix installation CD).
			</para>
			 <para>
				Both applications are simple to use and require no further explanation on how to use them, except for a small comment about “partition types”.
			</para>
			 <para>
				A hard drive space can be divided into no more than four “primary” partitions, which can be problematic if you are hosting more than one operating system on the same hard drive. A hard drive can, however, be divided into three “primary” partitions and one “extended” partition. The extended partition can then be subdivided into “logical” partitions and hence overcome the limitation set by the “primary partition” (i.e. no more than four partitions). In practice, there is no difference between a logical and a primary partition except for that “Windows” OS cannot be installed on a logical partition.
			</para>

		</section>
		
		 <section id="sect-Startup_Guide-Preparing_Salix_Installation-So_what_kind_of_partitions_do_you_need">
			<title>So what kind of partitions do you need?</title>
			 <orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Salix needs, at the very minimum, one partition which holds the root directory and must be assigned as “/” (without the quotation marks).
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						It is highly recommended to have one swap partition. If you already have another Linux OS running on your machine, its swap partition can be shared, and you do not need to create another. A swap partition size is in essence used as an extra RAM to improve the performance of your machine. If, for example, your machine doesn’t have a lot of physical RAM or you’re performing memory-intensive operations (such as video editing) that use up most or all of the physical RAM. It is normally recommended to have 1.5-2 times the size of your RAM, but for a modern desktop computer with more than a couple Gb of RAM, swap may not be necessary.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						It is also highly recommended to have one partition to hold your /home directory, where you can store all your personal data such as documents, photos, customised settings for the desktop environment etc.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						It is optional to have one partition to hold the /usr directory, where application files are stored (similar to the “Program Files” directory in Windows or the “/Apps” in Mac OS X).
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Optionally you can create one partition to hold the /var directory, where system log files are stored. But unless you are running a server machine, this is probably unnecessary.
					</para>
					 <para>
						An advantage of having more than one partition to hold separate directories is that you can reformat one partition without affecting others. For example, you can re-install Salix on your machine (and this goes to the partition holding the “/” directory) while leaving the partition holding the /home directory intact.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</orderedlist>
			 <para>
				Each partition can be formatted into one of several <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_file_systems">file systems</ulink>. Unless you have a particular favourite for a reason, we recommend you format your partitions with the ext4 file system.
			</para>

		</section>
		

	</section>
	
	 <section id="sect-Startup_Guide-Starting_Up_Salix_OS-Installing_from_a_Live_CD_USB">
		<title>Installing from a Live CD / USB</title>
		 <para>
			Salix Live Installer is found on the Desktop of every Live CD and is very easy to use. Contextual help triggered by the position of the mouse will be displayed above the application and will guide you every step of the way.
		</para>
		 <para>
			You will be greeted by a reminder that all the necessary partitions have to be created first. As we have seen, this can be done simply with the help of Gparted, which is included in Salix Live and is available directly on the desktop (see <xref linkend="sect-Startup_Guide-Salix_Live_Tools-Gparted" />).
		</para>
		 <mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="./images/46a995ce.png" width="500" />
			</imageobject>
			 <textobject>
				<phrase>Screenshot of Salix Live Installer</phrase>
			</textobject>

		</mediaobject>
		 <para>
			On the left side of the application, you will notice the different sections that must be configured before launching the installation process: Time, Keyboard, Locale, Partitions, Users and Software. Clicking on one of these sections will display the corresponding options that need to be set. As you progress through the configuration process, a check will be displayed beside each completed section. Only when all the sections have been completed will the “Launch Salix Install” button be activated.
		</para>
		 <para>
			So do take the time to familiarise yourself fully with Salix Live Installer. Undo options are available and none of the settings will be applied until you click on the “Launch Salix Install” button.
		</para>
		 <para>
			Remember that the existing swap partition will be automatically used by the Live installer without any prompting on your part.
		</para>
		 <para>

		</para>
		 <mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="./images/1289aa62.png" width="500" />
			</imageobject>
			 <textobject>
				<phrase>Screenshot of Salix Live Installer partitions configuration</phrase>
			</textobject>

		</mediaobject>
		 <para>
			Salix comes with three different installation modes. The Full installation mode includes a range of useful applications one could need on a daily basis while following the "one application per task" rationale, while the Basic Mode provides a user with a graphical desktop environment, a web browser and Gslapt package manager (see <xref linkend="sect-Startup_Guide-Package_Management-Gslapt" />).
		</para>
		 <para>
			This is ideal for advanced users who would like to have the basic desktop environment installed first, and then to add their own choice of applications. The Core Mode installs the minimum software essential for a console system to start (i.e. a graphical environment is not provided). This is ideal if you are an experienced user and love to customise your installation for any specific purpose, such as a web server, file server and so on.
		</para>
		 <para>
			Once the installation process is completed, you will be given the choice to launch Lilo Setup to configure your LILO bootloader (see <xref linkend="sect-Startup_Guide-Salix_Tools-Lilo_Setup" />). Most of the time this is what you will want to do although occasionally, it might be preferable not to, for example if you want to use Grub instead or if you want to simply incorporate Salix into an existing bootloader configuration from another distribution in a multiple boot setup.
		</para>
		 <para>

		</para>
		 <mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="./images/609b5e05.png" width="500" />
			</imageobject>
			 <textobject>
				<phrase>Screenshot of Salix Live Installer packages option</phrase>
			</textobject>

		</mediaobject>
		 <para>
			Lilo Setup is also very easy to use. Contextual help triggered by the position of the mouse will also be displayed above the application and will guide you every step of the way.
		</para>
		 <para>
			Once Lilo is set up, you are good to go! You can re-start your machine, and start enjoying Salix time.
		</para>

	</section>
	
	 <section id="sect-Startup_Guide-Starting_Up_Salix_OS-Installing_from_a_Salix_Installation_CD">
		<title>Installing from a Salix Installation CD</title>
		 <para>
			Installing Salix from a Salix Installation CD is very similar to installing Slackware. Everything will be done efficiently in a semi-graphical command line interface.
		</para>
		 <orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Select your keymap.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					If you prefer to let Salix do everything including partition management, just select AUTOPARTITION. Note that this will delete everything on the hard drive.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Partition management with cfdisk – you can select the hard drive you would like to modify with the arrow keys and the space key.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					You can create a new partition by selecting a free disk space and choosing New. You will be asked to select “primary” partition / “extended” partition first and then set the size. Remember, you can have up to four primary partitions or three primary partition with one extended partition for more partitions. Let's say we want to create one swap partition and partitions for the “/” and “/home” directories.
				</para>
				 <para>
					To create a swap partition, for example, select “primary” partition. Hit enter (for the default starting cylinder), and then type in “+1024M” for 1024 Mb. Choose Type to specify the file system type. Enter 82 (Linux swap).
				</para>
				 <para>
					Let's assume that you have already used up the first three primary partitions, the last one should be made into an “extended” partition as you would still like to create the partitions for “/” and for “/home”.
				</para>
				 <para>
					To create an extended partition, select “extended” partition. Hit enter and again hit enter for the default value. This will create an extended partition out of the remaining disk space.
				</para>
				 <para>
					Now select Free disk space from the extended partition, and create New. Create a “logical” partition as you did for the primary partition. Set the size to “+10240M” for roughly 10 Gb. This will be your partition for the root directory (“/”). Select Type, and type “83” (Linux partition).
				</para>
				 <para>
					Create again a new partition and this time, accept all the default selections. The remaing disk space will be put in this partition. This will be your partition for the “/home” directory. Select Type, and type “83”.
				</para>
				 <para>
					Select Write, and then Quit to exit the partition management.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Your swap partition will be automatically detected. Say “yes” if the detected partition corresponds to that.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					You will then be asked to specify the partition for the root “/” directory. Select the partition you have created for the “/”, and continue to format the partition. The ext4 file system is recommended here.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					If you have other partitions to mount, you can do so. As we have a partition for a “/home” directory, we select the partition and continue. Unless the partition is new or you would like to erase the content of this partition, select not to format.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Other partitions such as Windows partitions will be detected automatically. If you would like to make those partitions automatically usable during your Salix session, include them all to mount.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The installer will start installing Salix. You will be asked first where the source files are. As you are installing from the CD, select “from the CD”. Everything should be detected automatically.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					You will be asked to choose an installation mode (Full, Basic or Core).
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Installation of packages will start.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					After the installation, LILO set up will start up. Unless you are not using LILO, choose the default options.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					You will be asked for some other questions regarding time-zone, user name and root password (superuser / administrator password). When all the basic questions are answered, the machine will restart itself.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					That's all. The computer is good to go! Enjoy Salix!
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</orderedlist>

	</section>
	
	 <section id="sect-Startup_Guide-Starting_Up_Salix_OS-Installing_from_a_Salix_Installation_USB">
		<title>Installing from a Salix Installation USB</title>
		 <para>
			Installing Salix OS from a USB key is also possible (but consider installing from a Salix Live USB also). The most difficult part is to know the device name of your USB key. You may wish to issue the command “fdisk -l” as root to know which device is used for your USB key.
		</para>
		 <orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Create your USB stick with <ulink url="http://unetbootin.sourceforge.net/">unetbootin</ulink>
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					At Salix installation chose "Install from hard disk"
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Enter the device of your USB stick: This probably is /dev/sdb1 if you only have one hard disk. Please note that a Few sticks are mounted by /dev/sdb instead of /dev/sdb1
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The next dialog asks where the Salix packages are located on the USB stick. The correct answer here is /salix
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Installation should continue normally
				</para>
				 <para>
					Alternatively, you can mount your USB key first.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</orderedlist>
		 <orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					After starting up the set up screen, select your keyboard type and exit the setup
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Type “mkdir /salix” (without the quotation marks)
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Type “mount /dev/sdb /salix” (sdb can be sdb1, depending on the assignment by your machine)
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Type setup to restart the installation process
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					When asked for the source file, select “from a local directory” and type in “/salix/salix”
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Installation should continue normally
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</orderedlist>

	</section>
	

</chapter>

